Brian Ssekalegga

ssekalegga@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/ssekalegga-brian

Summary

Experienced Information Communication Technology professional with a demonstrated history of web application development.

Throughout my 5+ years of front-end development, I have led the implementation of several business platforms in the micro-finance and agribusiness sector.

Most recently, I led the development of Patasente website and web application e-wallet for SMEs in Uganda.

Experience

Event security quard

Jan 2022 - Present

Securtrust Protection - Ontario Canada

- Manages groups of party goers to safely attend and also depart from concert.
- Ensures that event audience maintained Covid SOPs during events.

Web Application Developer Feb 2017 – Present

Patasente limited Uganda (2017 -2021 Full time ,2022 - Present

Part Time)

- Working with a team of four developers to understand client requirements, design creative prototypes and translate them into application features.
- Collaborates with the team to develop wireframes, mockups and prototypes, perform unit and integration testing.

 Transformed their online payment system which led to increase of transactions to almost \$350,000 monthly.

Material Controller and data entry Jan 2019 - Mar 2020

Sycreon - Vaughan Ontario Canada

- Ensured that I met all daily, weekly and monthly quotes and it reduced the amount of time returned damaged products stay on the production line.
- · Awarded Attendance of the month in 2018.

Freelance Web Designer Nov 2018 - Jan 2019

Tomlinson Lifestyle Medicine Consulting - Ontario Canada

- Redesigned the company website which increased more user traffic.
- Discussed options with the client to make sure websites meet the firm's needs.

Education

Humber College - Ontario Canada

Postgraduate Certificate, Web Development Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

Web Development graduate certificate program focuses on the development of websites and web services for multiple environments including database-driven programming, content management systems and mobile services.

Team University - Kampala UgandaBachelor's degree in Information Technology Jul 2015 - Jul 2018

This program enables IT professionals to design, implement, customize and manage technologies hence gaining the knowledge and skills to match information technology products and services with business goals.

Skills

HTML • MySQL • JavaScript • SQL • PHP • Bootstrap • Figma (Software) • Laravel • Vuejs • React • Nodejs • MongoDb • C# • Project Management

Licenses & Certifications

Security license - Ontario Government **Transcript** - Team University

Honors & Awards

Winner of ICT – Innovative Apps Category - Ministry of Gender, Labour and Social Development Uganda Aug 2015

National Youth Talent Expo Awards aimed at recognising the invaluable contribution of young people to development at community and national level.

Attendance Award - Sycreon Aug 2018